this video is sponsored by Wizards of
the Coast welcome to the next part of
this series where I'm reviewing the four
Doctor Who Commander Decks that have
just launched the four new command decks
come with 50 brand new Doctor Who
inspired cards as well as 10 Doctor Who
plane Chase cards all the cards in these
deck have incredible new artwork which I
can't wait to show you in this video
I'll be going through the masters of
evil commander deck covering the best
new cards the best rep prints and cards
that I would be looking to add to
upgrade the deck now without further Ado
let's jump into masters of evil Alon Z
masters of evil is a blue red black
commander deck that is helmed by either
Davos Dar Creator or Missy this deck is
all about summoning a massive Army of
DARS or Cybermen you will be deleted and
putting your opponents through some
villainous choices where no matter what
they'll pick you'll always come out on
top not only that it features a gallery
of villains from the entirety of Doctor
Who's history out of the four decks this
is easily my favorite one and one that I
personally think is a top Contender for
being the strongest out of the four
let's take a closer look at the face
commanders of this deck starting with
Davos D Creator a four minor grixis
legendary alien scientist a 34 that says
Menace at the beginning of your endep
create a 33 dalic artifact creature
token with Menace if an opponent lost
three or more life this turn then each
opponent who lost three or more life
this turn faces a villainous choice you
draw a card or that player discards a
card next we have Missy a six Manor
grixis Legendary Time Lord Rogue a 45
that says whenever another non-artifact
creature dies return it to the
battlefield under your control face down
and tapped it's a 22 Cyberman artifact
creature and at the beginning of your
end step each opponent faces a
villainous Choice each artifact creature
you control deals one damage to that
opponent or you draw a card and Chaos in
shoes I really like both of these face
commanders while Missy is not only one
of the most flavorful cards in this deck
her ability requires absolutely no input
from you to be good as creatures dying
is just a natural part of the game of
course if you do put a little bit of
effort in you'll be summoning an army of
Cybermen in no time Davos on the other
hand does require some work to get going
but thanks to D's naturally being 33s
and having Menace triggering his ability
is a piece of cake so which one should
be helming your deck well I personally
would go with Missy but let's take a
look at some of my favorite new cards
that you might look to build around
ashad the lone Cyberman is a four Mana
grixis legendary artifact Cyberman a 33
that says the first non-legendary
artifact spell you can cast each turn
has casualty two as you cast the spell
you sacrifice a creature with power two
or greater which coincidentally the
Cyberman tokens have two power when you
do that you get a copy of the spell his
second ability says whenever you
sacrifice another creature put a plus
one plus1 counter on a Shard there are
many artifacts you'll want to copy in
this deck and simply sacrificing a 22 to
get a copy is more than a fair price the
ones I would be looking to copy is the
Cyberman Squadron a seven Mana 55
artifact creature that says non-
legendary artifacts you control have
Myriad and yes Myriad does stack so with
two copies of this on the battlefield
you'll get six additional copies of any
non-legendary artifact creature you
attack with and this next card goes
great with both ashard and the Cyberman
Squadron let's check out Dal drone a
five Mana black 33 Dal with flying and
Menace that's says
exterminate when Dar drone enters the
battlefield destroy Target creature and
opponent controls that player loses
three life while on the surface this
isn't a very flashy card at the bare
minimum this card is a two for one with
relevant creature typing that only gets
better when combined with the previously
mentioned cards now while we don't get
any doctors in this deck we do get four
other versions of the master each
standing completely apart from the last
and remaining being ever so flavorful my
two favorite iterations are the master
multiplied a six minor ratos Legendary
Time log Rogue a 43 that has Myriad and
the legend rule doesn't apply to
creature tokens you control and
triggered abilities you control can't
cause you to sacrifice or Exile creature
tokens you control just to make sure
we're on the same page Myriad is a
special ability that says whenever you
attack a player with a creature with
myriad add for each opponent you create
a copy of that creature tapped and
attacking that player or planes Walker
they control Exile those tokens at the
end of combat so with the master
multiplied in play you can attack a
player and get three more copies of the
master and assuming they all live till
the next turn the next time you attack
each Master will create more copies of
themselves and you can see how this can
get out of hand really easily and this
effect doesn't just apply to the master
if you manage to play the new card darac
Squadron the turn before the master
multiplied you'll get to keep all of the
dalac Squadron tokens when they attack
too my next favorite Master is the
master mesmerist a four Mana deir
Legendary Time Lord Rogue a 33 that says
tap Target creature and opponent
controls with power less than or equal
to the Master's power gain skull until
end of turn goit and whenever a creature
with skull deals combat damage to one of
your opponents put a plus one plus1
counter on the master and draw a card
again incredibly flavorful there's
nothing like making your opponents fight
amongst themselves while the master sits
back and gets stronger and draws more
cards one final Legend I want to talk
about is vizor turu the only doctor's
companion card without a doctor in the
deck to pair it with and for obvious law
reasons visw is a Forman black legendary
Rogue a 25 with deal with the black
Guardian when vizor enters the
battlefield you may have an opponent
gain control of it if you do it's goed
for as long as they control it and at
the beginning of your end step draw a
card and then you lose life equal to the
number of cards in your hand another
brilliantly flavorful card Vis law
effectively portrays whoever's control
he sits under slowly draining their life
away the one thing I think that was
missing from this card is an effect to
stop your opponent from sacrificing him
like the one on John irenicus shattered
one either way a well-designed card
before we go any further I just want to
remind you that if you pick up one of
these four decks and you want to bling
them out the Doctor Who collector
boosters are the way to do it inside
each pack you'll get 15 Doctor Who cards
from across the four Commander decks 12
of them will be foil and six to seven of
of them will have extended art will come
in the new Tardis showcase frame there
are even serialized doctors available
and you can pick them up from your local
game store now right back to the cards
looking at some of the non-legendary
cards I can't not talk about the Weeping
Angel related cards as they are
incredibly fun let's start with the
namesake card weeping angel weeping
angel is a three Mana Demir alien angel
a 2 two with flash first strike and
vigilance whenever an opponent casts a
creature spell weeping angel isn't a
creature until end of turn and if
weeping angel would deal combat damage
to a creature prevent that damage and
that creature's owner shuffles it into
their Library so basically when your
opponent casts a creature spell the
angels all turn into statues and when
they do manage to deal combat damage to
one of their creatures they effectively
blink them out of existence speaking of
blink is a four Manor deir Saga which is
the first Saga to my knowledge to
effectively bounce between two chapter
abilities on chapters 1 and three you
Shuffle away a creature and its owner
investigates on chapters 2 and four you
create a weeping angel token Sands the
combat damage ability shuffling
creatures into libraries is an
underrated effect as it prevents any
dies triggers from happening another
brilliant nod in this deck is the
addition of the laser screwdriver the
three other Commander decks all come
with the Doctor's sonic screwdrivers but
here we of course have the Master's
laser
screwdriver I love how these two cards
mirror each other the laser screwdriver
Taps artifacts instead of untapping them
it surveils instead of scrying and some
would consider that an upgrade and it
forces one of your opponent's creatures
to attack and do the dirty work for you
instead of heroically charging into the
battle yourself in terms of the best
reprints in this deck snuff out and
wound reflection are the clear winners
here as they've only been printed a
couple of times before this deck the
deck also comes with two Horizon lands
which have only been printed once before
and of course we have to give another
honorable mention to the two talismans
Talisman of dominance and Talisman of
indulgence for their brilliant artwork
if you're looking for ways to upgrade
this deck there are a couple of
different routes you can go down
depending on who your commander is if
Missy is is your commander the first
card I would be looking to add is
maressa the Black Rose marchesa's
ability grants your creatures Dethrone
and allows you to put plus one plus one
counters on any Cyberman that Missy
creates for you if those Cyberman cards
happen to be face down creatures when
they die they come back into play face
up under your control so even if your
army of Cybermen gets wiped out if they
had plus one plus1 counters on them you
instantly get to rebuild your army Missy
also works really well with morph
creatures if one of your morph creatures
gets turned into a Cyberman by Miss's
ability or any other ability you can
turn it face up by paying its morph cost
there's also a simple infinite combo
involving Missy ruthless Ripper and a
card like ashnod's alter for Davos we
want to ensure that each of our
opponents are losing three life during
each of our turns so we can maximize
that villainous Choice ability so it
might be worth Switching gears slightly
and leaning more into to a spell heavier
deck and include cards like gutter snipe
kessig flame breather and electrostatic
field and for instance and sorceries
utilize cards like rankles prank flame
Rift and blood tithe you could also look
into the discard route and run
enchantments like liliana's caress mrim
and blood Chief's Ascension and drain
your opponent out of both resources and
life so which of the new cards are your
favorite from this deck don't forget to
check out our previous Doctor Who
Commander review where I cover the best
cards from the timey Wy deck and keep an
eye out for our next Doctor Who video
have a good night and I'll see you in
the next one